

AKASH DASWANI DEVOPS/AWS/SYSTEMS ENGINEER



Flat No. 402, 63 Sundar Residency, Sector 1 Jawahar Nagar, Jaipur, Rajasthan, 302004

<u>akashdaswani6@gmail.com</u>

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/akashdaswani-bba571175

PERSONAL PROFILE

Pleasing youthful personality with a zest for life, knowledge and sound understanding of technology. Fruitful combination of academic expertise and leadership qualities inherent in the working style resulted into the recognition of the team at various occasion.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Cloud

Monitoring

Operating Systems	RHEL/CentOS 6.x/7.x/8, Ubuntu
Build/Automation Tools	Ansible, Maven, Jenkins, Terraform
Scripting	Shell, Bash
Web/App Server	Apache, Tomcat, Nginx
Ticketing Tools	JIRA, Autofix
Version Control Tools	GIT, Bitbucket, Azure devops repo
Container Tools	Docker, Docker Compose, Kubernetes.

Cloud Aws (S3, EC2, Route53, Cloud Watch, VPC etc)

Cloud watch, Nagios

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Torry Harris Business Solutions (Banglore)

DevOps Engineer | July 2021-PRESENT

- Giving support for the chat bot newly released by EE on GCP Cloud, Dialogflow service is used to create messaging bots that responds to customer and assign an agent to them
- Monitoring dialog flow logs
- Monitoring liveperson weather the chat is getting assigned
- ♦ Raising incident using autofix ticketing
- Providing support during maintenance, implementation, or upgradation
- ♦ Keeping check on active session in Dialog Flow
- Responsible for night-time on-call support for production changes and participated in 24/7 ON-CALL support to troubleshoot and manage deployments

TeamItServe (Texas)

DevOps Engineer | Jan 2021-July 2021

- System Administration for Linux Servers in development & production environment.
- Monitoring health and status of production servers ,administration of virtual machines running on
 VM ware server also configuring login permissions, network, and disk and installing packages/applications.
- ♦ User administration and configuring SSH.
- ♦ Install and configure Apache and Nginx Web Server and configuring SSL support.
- Automation of task using Shell script and CRON job.
- Observing the disk usages and Log file consumptions in Servers.
- ♦ Manage and resolve problems assigned by support/monitoring team.
- Created sprints in azure DevOps portal.
- ◆ Created the CI CD pipeline for the different environments.
- ♦ Experience with NAGIOS to monitor the application's performance
- Automated the infra deployment using terraform.
- ◆ Created Highly available environment

ADHOC NETWORK PVT LTD

DEVOPS ENGINEER | MAR 2020-Dec 2020

- Experience in creating Docker containers leveraging existing Linux containers and AMI's in addition to creating docker containers from scratch.
- ♦ Maintaining DNS and DHCP records and virtual networks
- Create, Develop and test environments of different applications by provisioning Kubernetes clusters on AWS using Docker, Ansible and Terraform.
- ♦ Deploy, manage, and maintain applications and systems deployed to AWS Cloud
- Managed multiple AWS Accounts with multiple VPC's for both production and non-prod.
- Pro-actively look for ways to enhance the functionality, reliability, operation of the pipeline.
- ♦ Experience working with AWS cloud and DevOps and Linux Administrator
- Troubleshooting the servers
- Written Playbooks to configure the multiple servers.
- Created weekly maintenance and monitoring reports
- ♦ Worked on Jenkins to create CI-CD pipeline using Git, docker, maven to deploy java based application
- Worked on Github to maintain the repositories.
- ◆ Performed as Sysadmin, environment includes Linux System Administration, Cloud hosting, and server-side scripting, transition into a DevOps role.
- ♦ Good understanding of SDLC, Agile methodologies and process

EDUCATIONAL HISTORY

AGARWAL COLLEGE (UNIVERSITY OF RAJASTHAN)

BCA | APRIL 2015- MARCH 2018

Percentage - 62% [First division]

Studied project planning, coordination, and ethics Worked with various startups on launching new apps and services

ST. SOLDIER PUBLIC SCHOOL, JAIPUR

COMMERCE, XII CLASS | APRIL 2014- MARCH 2015

PERSONAL DETAILS

Gender: Male

DOB: 7th March,1997

Languages: English, Hindi

Nationality: Indian